your-life.com 2019-04-14

# WCD - Privacy Statement

This website (hereinafter the “ _Website_ “) is provided by Bayer Inc..(hereinafter “ _us_ ” or “ _we_ ”). For further information regarding the provider of the Website, please refer to our imprint. 

Handling of personal data

In the following we wish to provide you with information on how we handle your personal data when you use our Website. Unless otherwise indicated in the following chapters, the legal basis for the handling of your personal data results from the fact that such handling is required to make available the functionalities of the Website requested by you (Art. 6(1)(b) General Data Protection Regulation).

Using our Website

Accessing our Website

When you call up our Website, your browser will transfer certain data to our web server. This is done for technical reasons and required to make available to you the requested information. To facilitate your access to the Website, the following data are collected, briefly stored and used: 

  * IP address
  * date and time of access
  * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  * Content of request (specific site)
  * Status of access/HTTP status code
  * Transferred volume of data
  * Website requesting access
  * Browser, language settings, version of browser software operating system and surface

Moreover, to protect our legitimate interests, we will store such data for a limited period of time in order to be able to initiate a tracking of personal data in the event of actual or attempted unauthorized access to our servers (Art. 6(1)(f) General Data Protection Regulation).

Setting of cookies

What are cookies?

This Website uses so-called “cookies”. Cookies are small text files that are stored in the memory of your terminal via your browser. They store certain information (e.g. your preferred language or site settings) which your browser may (depending on the lifespan of the cookie) retransmit to us upon your next visit to our Website.

What cookies do we use?

We differentiate between two categories of cookies: (1) functional cookies, without which the functionality of our Website would be reduced, and (2) optional cookies used for e.g. website analysis and marketing purposes. The following tables contain a detailed description of the optional cookies we use:

Optional Cookies

Name | Purpose and content | Lifespan | Provider | Consent  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics  |  Web analysis: 

These Cookies enable us to analyse your use of this website by assigning a unique and randomly generated ID to your device that lets us recognize your device upon your next visit.

| 6 months | Google Inc. |   
  
Doubleclick |  Online behavioral advertising

These cookies assign a randomly generated ID to your device, enabling us and our partners to recognize your device upon your next access. For details on behavioral advertising please see the respective chapter below. 

| 6 months | Google Inc. |   
  
WT_FPC | The anonymous identification of a visit for statistical analysis in order to optimize the website. No personal data is collected. |  1 year | Webtrends | Opt-out  
WTTimeIteration | The anonymous identification of the duration of the visit for statistical analysis in order to optimize the website. No personal data is collected. | 30 minutes | Webtrends | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_exp _EXPERIMENT_ID _goal_GOAL_ID | This cookie is generated when a goal is made. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_test_cookie | This is a session (temporary) cookie generated to detect if the cookies are enabled on the browser of the user or not. | Duration of the session: the cookie is deleted when the browser is closed. | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_exp _EXPERIMENT_ID_combi | This cookie is generated when users reach a particular combination. This makes sure that users see the same variation that they earlier saw when they visited the page. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_exp _EXPERIMENT_ID_exclude | This cookie is generated when a user has been excluded from a campaign. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_exp _EXPERIMENT_ID_split | This cookie is generated during a Split URL test. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_s | This cookie detects if the user is new or returning to a particular campaign. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vis_opt_out | This cookie indicates that the visitor is not part of the campaign. It is valid for 10 years. | 10 years | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
EXPERIMENT ID | Refers to the ID of the campaign and the GOAL ID refers to the ID of the goal. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
_vwo_uuid | This cookie generates a unique ID for every visitor and is used for the report segmentation feature in VWO, and it also allows you to view data in a more refined manner. If you have the campaign running on multiple domains, you will notice campaign specific UUID values. | 100 days | Visual Website Optimizer | Opt-out  
3ME_cookie | This cookie is generated when a user stays longer than 3 minutes on the website and is used for statistical analysis in order to optimize the website. No personal data is collected. | Duration of the session: the cookie is deleted when the browser is closed. | Bayer | Opt-out function not available  
  
Subject to your consent

We only use optional cookies if we have obtained your prior consent (Art. 6(1)(a) General Data Protection Regulation). Upon your first access to our Website, a banner will appear, asking you to give us your consent to the setting of optional cookies. If your consent is given, we will place a cookie on your computer and the banner will not appear again as long as the cookie is active. After expiration of the cookie’s lifespan, or if you actively delete the cookie, the banner will reappear upon your next visit to our Website and again ask for your consent.

How to prevent the setting of cookies

Of course you may use our Website without any cookies being set. In your browser, you can at any time configure or completely deactivate the use of cookies. This may, however, lead to a restriction of the functions or have adverse effects on the user-friendliness of our Website. You may at any time object to the setting of optional cookies by using the respective objection option indicated in the table above.

Website Analysis

On our Website we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“Google”).

Google will analyze your use of our Website on our behalf. To this purpose we use the cookies described in more detail in the above table. The information collected by Google in connection with your use of our Website (e.g. the referring URL, our webpages visited by you, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the US, where it will be stored and analyzed. The respective results will then be made available to us in anonymized form. Your usage data will not be connected to your full IP address during this process. We have activated on our Website the IP anonymizing function offered by Google, which will delete the last 8 bits (type IPv4) or the last 80 bits (type IPv6) of your IP address. Moreover, Google is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield, which ensures that an adequate level of data protection is maintained with respect to the processing of data by Google in the US.

You may revoke your consent to the use of web analysis at any time, either by downloading and installing the provided Google Browser Plugin or by administrating your consents in the above table, in which case an opt-out cookie will be placed. Both options will prevent the application of web analysis only as long as you use the browser on which you installed the plugin and do not delete the opt-out Cookie. Further information on Google Analytics is available in the Google Analytics Terms of Use, the Privacy and Data Protection Guidelines of Google Analytics and in the Google Privacy Policy.

Use of Visual Website Optimizer

Our website uses a testing tool from Visual Website Optimizer (http://visualwebsiteoptimizer.com) to determine specific statistical values regarding the use of our services. The tool anonymously collects measured data. This test uses cookies to recognise computer systems. The run time of these cookies is limited to the duration of the test. IP addresses are not saved in the process. You can opt out of having your anonymously collected data stored in the future at any time. ([http://visualwebsiteoptimizer.com/opt-out.php]())

Online behavioral advertising

This Website uses DoubleClick, a so-called targeted advertising service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“Google“).

Google will analyze your use of this Website. To this purpose we use the cookies described in more detail in the above table. The information collected by Google in connection with your use of our Website (e.g. the referring URL, our webpages visited by you, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the US, where it will be stored and analyzed. We and our partner Google will use this information to better tailor our advertisements to you and your interests, to limit the number of times you are shown the same advertisement, to evaluate the efficiency of promotional campaigns, and to better comprehend the behavior of visitors after they have looked at a certain ad. When you visit another website of the so-called “Google Display Network”, customized pop-ups tailored to your interests can be presented to you on the basis of the information collected on our Website.

You may withdraw your consent to this type of analysis of your use of this Website at any time either by administrating your consents in the above table, in which case an opt-out cookie will be placed, or by downloading and installing the Google Browser Plugin offered by Google. Both options will prevent the use of web analysis only as long as you use the browser on which you installed the plugin and do not delete the opt-out Cookie. Further information on Google DoubleClick is available on the Google Data Protection Guidelines for Advertising.

Use of contact forms

You can contact us directly via the contact forms available on our Website. In particular, you may provide us with the following information:

  * Name, surname, gender and title
  * Contact data (e.g. E-Mail address, phone number)
  * Message

We collect, process and use the information provided by you via the contact forms exclusively for the processing of your specific request.

External services or content on our Website

We include third-party services and/or content on our Website. When you use such third-party services or when third-party content is displayed, communication data are exchanged between you and the respective provider for technical reasons.

The respective provider of the services or content may also process your data for own additional purposes. To the best of our knowledge, we have configured the services and content of providers known to process data for own purposes in such a way that either any communication for other purposes than to present their services or content on our Website is blocked, or communication only takes place once you have actively opted to use the respective service. However, since we have no control over data collected and processed by third parties, we are not in a position to provide binding information regarding the scope and purpose of such processing of your data.

For further information regarding the scope and purpose of such collection and processing of your data, please consult the privacy statements of the providers whose services and/or content we include and who are responsible for the protection of your data in this context:

Use of the recommendation function

If you wish to recommend us to others, you can do so by using the recommendation function on our Website. You may, in your and our legitimate interest, send a message to any person if you assume that the recipient wishes to receive such information.

Persons, who do not wish to receive messages via our recommendation function, may request to be included in a list of blocked recipients by following the directions included in the respective message.

Information on side effects and quality complaints

This Website is not intended or designed for communications regarding side effects, lack of therapeutic effect, medication errors, grey market products/counterfeit medicine, incorrect or off-label use, quality complaints and/or other issues regarding the safeness or quality of Bayer products. If you wish to report side effects or make a quality complaint, please contact your health care professional (e.g. physician or pharmacist), your local health authority, or use our Website for the report of undesirable side effects.

If you nevertheless report to us undesirable side effects or other issues regarding the safeness or quality of Bayer products, we will be legally bound to deal with your communication and may have to contact you for clarification purposes. Subsequently, we may have to notify the competent health authorities of the issues reported by you. In this context, your information will be forwarded in pseudonymized form, i.e. no information by which you may be directly identified will be passed on. We may also have to forward these pseudonymized notifications to our group companies and cooperation partners, to the extent these are likewise obliged to notify their respectively competent health authorities.

Transfer of data for commissioned processing

For the processing of your data we will to some extent use specialized service contractors. Such service contractors are carefully selected and regularly monitored by us. Based on respective data processor agreements, they will only process personal data upon our instruction and strictly in accordance with our directives.

Information regarding your rights

The following rights are in general available to you according to applicable data privacy laws:

  * Right of information about your personal data stored by us;
  * Right to request the correction, deletion or restricted processing of your personal data;
  * Right to object to a processing for reasons of our own legitimate interest, public interest, or profiling , unless we are able to proof that compelling, warranted reasons superseding your interests, rights and freedom exist, or that such processing is done for purposes of the assertion, exercise or defense of legal claims;
  * Right to data portability;
  * Right to file a complaint with a data protection authority;
  * You may at any time with future effect revoke your consent to the collection, processing and use of your personal data. For further information please refer to the chapters above describing the processing of data based on your consent.

If you wish to exercise your rights, please address your request to the contact indicated below.

Contact

For any questions you may have with respect to data privacy, please use the provided contact form or contact our company data protection officer at the following address:

Group Data Protection Officer  
Bayer AG  
51368 Leverkusen

Amendment of Privacy Statement

We may update our Privacy Statement from time to time. Updates of our Privacy Statement will be published on our Website. Any amendments become effective upon publication on our Website. We therefore recommend that you regularly visit the site to keep yourself informed on possible updates.

Last updated: 16.05.2018.
